Edwin T. Dahlberg Papers
Edwin T. Dahlberg Papers
- Sermons
  - "The Preacher and His Bible" (Box 16)
  - "Preacher, Teacher, and Healer" (Box 16)
  - "Preaching As We Go" (Box 16)
  - "The Preaching of Jesus" (Box 16)
  - "Preaching What We Practice" (Box 16)
  - "Precious Stones" (Box 16)
  - "Prelude to Faith" (Box 16)
  - "Preparation for a Better Family Life" (Box 16)
  - "Preparing the Way" (Box 16)
  - "The Pressure of Humanity Upon Jesus" (Box 16)
  - "The Price of the Bible" (Box 16)
  - "Prison Reform in Israel" (Box 16)
  - "The Prize Not Yet Obtained" (Box 16)
  - "The Prodigal's Older Brother" (Box 16)
  - "The Prodigal Son" (Box 16)
  - "A Program for the Local Church" (Box 16)
  - "The Promises of God" (Box 16)
  - "The Promise of Power" (Box 16)
  - "The Proof of Conversion" (Box 16)
  - "The Prophet of the Broken Home" (Box 16)
  - "The Prophet of the Exile" (Box 16)
  - "A Prophetic Religion" (Box 16)
  - "Protestant D.P. Re-settlement" The Protestant Hour (Box 16)
  - "The Protestant Revival" (Box 16)
  - "The Protestant Witness in a Divided World" (Box 16)
  - "Protestantism: Co-operation or Union" (Box 16)
  - "Protestantism in Puerto Rico" (Box 16)
  - "A Psalm of the Airways" (Box 16)
  - "The Psalmist Comes to Onondaga County" (Box 16)
  - "The Purpose of the Church" (Box 16)
  - "The Quiet Hour" (Box 16)
  - "The Quitter" (Box 16)
  - "Rachel Weeping for Her Children" (Box 16)
  - "The Radicalism of Pentecost" (Box 16)
  - Radio Dialogue Sermon in Baptist Church, Syracuse, N.Y. (Box 16)
  - Radio Meditations-KXLW (Box 16)
  - Radio Services (Box 16)
  - "The Ragged Regiment" (Box 16)
  - "Walter Rauschenbusch: Prophet of Social Christianity" (Box 16)
  - "The Reapers Are Angels" (Box 16)
  - "Reality in Evangelism" (Box 16)
  - Reception Address-Maple Street Baptist Church" (Box 16)
  - "The Rechabites" (Box 16)
  - "Recruits for the New Church" (Box 16)
  - "The Redemption of the City" (Box 17)
  - "Reformation Sunday and the Protestant Revival" (Box 17)
  - "The Rejected Stone" (Box 17)
  - "Religion and Health" (Box 17)
  - "Religion and Labor" (Box 17)
  - "Religion and the State" (Box 17)
  - "Religion as Deliverance" (Box 17)
  - "The Religion of Jack Miller" (Box 17)
  - "The Religion of Jesus" (Box 17)
  - "The Religion of Marshall Foch" (Box 17)
  - "The Religion of Middle Age" (Box 17)
  - "The Religion of Pleasure" (Box 17)
  - "A Religion of Power" (Box 17)
  - "Religion Rides the Ox" (Box 17)
  - "Religious Education in the Modern City" (Box 17)
  - "Religious Liberty and Stewardship" (Box 17)
  - "The Religious Ministry of the Church Related Hospital" (Box 17)
  - "The Religious Service of Maturity" (Box 17)
  - "Religious Understanding" (Box 17)
  - "In Remembrance of Our Lord" (Box 17)
  - "The Renewal of a Right Spirit" (Box 17)
  - "Renewing the Church" (Box 17)
  - "A Repentant City" (Box 17)
  - "Replenishing Our Resources" (Box 17)
  - "Resistance Movements Against Christianity" (Box 17)
  - "The Resources of God" (Box 17)
  - "The Resurgence of the Non-Christian Religions" (Box 17)
  - "Resurrection and Righteousness" (Box 17)
  - "Resurrection and Victory" (Box 17)
  - "Resurrection of a City"'' (Box 17)
  - "The Return of an Old Fashioned Question" (Box 17)
  - "The Return to Religion" (Box 17)
  - "The Returning Word of God" (Box 17)
  - "The Revelation of God in Christ" (Box 17)
  - "The Revelation of Man in Christ" (Box 17)
  - "Reverse the Charges" (Box 17)
  - "Revivals-Can They Happen Again?" (Box 17)
  - "Revive the Church Library!" (Box 17)
  - "Revolutions Then and Now" (Box 17)
  - "The Rich Young Ruler" (Box 17)
  - "The Righteousness of God" (Box 17)
  - "Rightful Claims of God and the Church" (Box 17)
  - "The Rivers of Damascus" (Box 17)
  - "The Road Not Taken" (Box 17)
  - "Rock of Roger Williams" (Box 17)
  - "The Rock That Is Higher Than I" (Box 17)
  - "The Rote of the Prophet" (Box 17)
  - "The Roosevelt of the Old Testament" (Box 17)
  - "The Roots of Righteousness" (Box 17)
  - "Rose Gardens of the Soul" (Box 17)
  - "Rose Gardens of the Soul" (Box 17)
  - "The Royal Mile" (Box 17)
  - "The Royal Rainbow" (Box 17)
  - "The Sacrifices of God" (Box 17)
  - "The Sacrifices of Joy" (Box 17)
  - "The Sadducees" (Box 17)
  - "Salt of the Earth" (Box 17)
  - "Salt Free Christianity" (Box 17)
  - "Satan Attends a Press Conference" (Box 17)
  - "The Satisfactions of Building" (Box 17)
  - "Saved to the Uttermost" (Box 17)
  - "The Savior of the World" (Box 17)
  - "The Scarlet Line" (Box 17)
  - "Scattering the Gospel" (Box 17)
  - "The Sea Walls of Faith" (Box 17)
  - "The Second Coming of Christ and the First Coming of Democracy" (Box 17)
  - "The Second Mile" (Box 17)
  - "The Second Mile Campaign" (Box 17)
  - "The Second Oldest Man in the World" (Box 17)
  - "The Seeking Minister and the Saving Christ" (Box 17)
  - "The Sensational Preachers of the Bible" (Box 17)
  - "The Serene Life" (Box 17)
  - Sermons Delivered at Chautauqua (Box 17)
  - "The Servants Knew" (Box 17)
  - "Servants or Friends?" (Box 18)
  - "Seven Golden Candlesticks" (Box 18)
  - "Seventeen and Its Robes of Dreams" (Box 18)
  - "The Seventh Word" (Box 18)
  - "The Shadow of the Apostles" (Box 18)
  - "Shall We Abolish the Sunday School?" (Box 18)
  - "Shall We Revive the Imprecatory Psalms?" (Box 18)
  - "Shavings in the Tower" (Box 18)
  - "The Sheep Won!" (Box 18)
  - "The Shepherd of the World" (Box 18)
  - "The Shepherding God" (Box 18)
  - "The Shepherds' Recessional" (Box 18)
  - "Shoutings of Grace" (Box 18)
  - "Shouts Among the Stones" (Box 18)
  - "The Significance of Baptism" (Box 18)
  - "The Significance of Radio" (Box 18)
  - "Significant Youth Movements Today" (Box 18)
  - "Signs From Heaven" (Box 18)
  - "The Simplified Life" (Box 18)
  - "The Singing Disciple" (Box 18)
  - "A Singing Faith" (Box 18)
  - "The Sin of Evil Speaking" (Box 18)
  - "The Sin of Self-Consciousness" (Box 18)
  - "Thy Sins are Forgiven" (Box 18)
  - "Sins of the Sensitive" (Box 18)
  - "The Sky Watchers" (Box 18)
  - "Slow of Heart" (Box 18)
  - "Somewhere Along the Way" (Box 18)
  - "The Son of Man Uplifted" (Box 18)
  - "The Song of Deborah" (Box 18)
  - "A Song To March To" (Box 18)
  - "Sons of Encouragement" (Box 18)
  - "The Soul's Outer Drive" (Box 18)
  - "The Sovereignty of Christ" (Box 18)
  - "The Sovereignty of God" (Box 18)
  - "Sparrows in the Pepper-Trees" (Box 18)
  - "The Speaking River" (Box 18)
  - "Spears Against the Stars" (Box 18)
  - "The Specific Applications" (Box 18)
  - "The Spirit of Liberty" (Box 18)
  - "The Spirit of Obligation" (Box 18)
  - "The Spirit an the Highway" (Box 18)
  - "The Spirit of the Lord's Supper" (Box 18)
  - "Spiritual Amnesia" (Box 18)
  - "The Spiritual Man" (Box 18)
  - "The Star in the East" (Box 18)
  - "Statement an Universal Military Training" (Box 18)
  - "Stones in the Furrow" (Box 18)
  - "The Stones Will Cry Out" (Box 18)
  - "The Store Houses of Egypt" (Box 18)
  - "Strength for the New Day" (Box 18)
  - "The Strengthening Angel" (Box 18)
  - "The Struggle for Labor Democracy" (Box 18)
  - "The Student's Faith" (Box 18)
  - "The Success of the Christian's Loss" (Box 18)
  - "The Successful City Church" (Box 18)
  - "Successful Failures" (Box 18)
  - "Sufficient Unto the Day" (Box 18)
  - "The Sun Goeth Down" (Box 18)
  - "The Sword of King Arthur" (Box 18)
  - "The Sword or the Cross" (Box 18)
  - "Symphony of Victory." (Box 18)
  - "The Table Conversation of Jesus" (Box 18)
  - "Take Up Thy Cross" (Box 18)
  - "Taking Down the Angels" (Box 18)
  - "Taking Our Sins Seriously" (Box 18)
  - "Talitha Cumi" (Box 18)
  - "The Task Before Us" (Box 18)
  - "Tassels of Blue" (Box 18)
  - "The Teaching Church" (Box 18)
  - "Teaching the Gospel in the Space Age" (Box 18)
  - "The Temperance Revival" (Box 18)
  - "Temples of the Heart" (Box 18)
  - "Temples Still Undone" (Box 18)
  - "Temple of a Thousand Mizpahs" (Box 19)
  - "Temptations of Christ and the Church" (Box 19)
  - "The Ten Virgins" (Box 19)
  - "Ten Years in the Ministry" (Box 19)
  - "The Tents on the Old Camp Ground" (Box 19)
  - "New Testament Ideals of Motherhood" (Box 19)
  - "Thanksgiving For Our Faith" (Box 19)
  - "Thanksgiving in Christ" (Box 19)
  - "Thanksgiving in the Kingdom" (Box 19)
  - "The Thanksgiving of the Redeemed" (Box 19)
  - "Thanksgiving Seasons of the Soul" (Box 19)
  - "That's For Sure" (Box 19)
  - "There Go the Ships" (Box 19)
  - "There is Something Going On!" (Box 19)
  - "There Was Evening and There Was Morning" (Box 19)
  - "These All Died in Faith" (Box 19)
  - "These Also I Must Bring" (Box 19)
  - "They Dared to Believe" (Box 19)
  - "The Thief on the Cross" (Box 19)
  - "Things Honorable" (Box 19)
  - "The Things that are Caesar's" (Box 19)
  - "Thinkers Wanted" (Box 19)
  - "Thirty Pieces of Silver" (Box 19)
  - "This Is the Victory" (Box 19)
  - "Three Days With Christ" (Box 19)
  - "Three Towers" (Box 19)
  - "Thy Kingdom Come" (Box 19)
  - "Thy Kingdom Now!" (Box 19)
  - "The Tie That Binds Our Hearts" (Box 19)
  - "Till the Stars Appeared" (Box 19)
  - "Timber Line" (Box 19)
  - "The Time of Ignorance" (Box 19)
  - "The Time of Our Visitation" (Box 19)
  - "The Timeless Christ" (Box 19)
  - "Tired of the Rough Stuff" (Box 19)
  - "To Die Is Gain" (Box 19)
  - "Tom Sawyer and Huckleberry Firm" (Box 19)
  - "Toward the Great American Revival" (Box 19)
  - "The Tower of Babel" (Box 19)
  - "The Tower of Siloam" (Box 19)
  - "The Tower to Heaven" (Box 19)
  - "Trading Truth for a Lie" (Box 19)
  - "The Transfiguration" (Box 19)
  - "Transfusion of Blood" (Box 19)
  - "Translating the Bible Today" (Box 19)
  - "Treasures Old and New" (Box 19)
  - "The True Vine" (Box 19)
  - "The Trustworthiness of God" (Box 19)
  - "Truth Before" (Box 19)
  - "Truth and Freedom" (Box 19)
  - "Try" (Box 19)
  - "The Twelfth Witness" (Box 19)
  - "The Twelve Gates of the Holy City" (Box 19)
  - "The Twentieth Century and Life in the Fiery Furnace" (Box 19)
  - "Twice Warmed" (Box 19)
  - "Two Can Walk Together" (Box 19)
  - "Two Car Garages" (Box 19)
  - "Two Gardens" (Box 19)
  - "Two in One" (Box 19)
  - "Two Men Out of Work" (Box 19)
  - "The Unchanging Christ in a Changing World" (Box 19)
  - "Understanding Ourselves" (Box 19)
  - "Unexploded Shells" (Box 19)
  - "The Unfailing Lamp of God" (Box 19)
  - "The Unfinished Furrow" (Box 19)
  - "Uniformed Christianity" (Box 19)
  - "The Unitary Hope of the Christian Church" (Box 19)
  - "The Universal Invitation" (Box 19)
  - "Universal Military Training" (Box 19)
  - "The Universal Reformation" (Box 19)
  - "University By the Sea" (Box 19)
  - "The Unknown Country" (Box 19)
  - "Unknown Soldiers of Christ" (Box 19)
  - "The Unseen Presence" (Box 19)
  - "Unshaken As Eternal Hills" (Box 19)
  - "Until We Find a Better Way" (Box 19)
  - "The Unusual Life" (Box 19)
  - "Up From Success to Life" (Box 19)
  - "Up From the Gates of Dawn" (Box 19)
  - "The Urgent Christ" (Box 19)
  - "The Urgent Harvest" (Box 19)
  - "Vacant Houses" (Box 20)
  - "Values of 1921" (Box 20)
  - "Vanished Visions" (Box 20)
  - "Vices of the Virtuous" (Box 20)
  - "The Victorious Consequences of Faith in the Son of God" (Box 20)
  - "The Victory Campaign" (Box 20)
  - "The Victory Through Christ" (Box 20)
  - "Victory Through Our Lord Jesus Christ" (Box 20)
  - "The Victory Year" (Box 20)
  - "The Vision of God in Christ" (Box 20)
  - "Visions of God" (Box 20)
  - "A Voice from the Cloud" (Box 20)
  - "The Voice in the Wilderness" (Box 20)
  - "The Voice of the Congregation" (Box 20)
  - "The Voice Today" (Box 20)
  - "Walking By Faith" (Box 20)
  - "Walking Up the Churches" (Box 20)
  - "Walking Where Jesus Walked" (Box 20)
  - "Wallace Reid's Last Prayer" (Box 20)
  - "Wanted: More Room for God's Blessings" (Box 20)
  - "Was Peter the First Pope?" (Box 20)
  - "The Waters of Marah" (Box 20)
  - "The Way of Escape" (Box 20)
  - "We Believe-And Tremble" (Box 20)
  - "We Choose Christ" (Box 20)
  - "We Have Good News!" (Box 20)
  - "We Have Peace" (Box 20)
  - "We Have Seen the Messiah" (Box 20)
  - "We Invade the World" (Box 20)
  - "We Preach Christ Crucified" (Box 20)
  - "We Read It Through J" (Box 20)
  - "We Would See Jesus" (Box 20)
  - "The Weightier Matter" (Box 20)
  - "Welcome to Rev. Earl Adams" (Box 20)
  - "The Well Is Deep" (Box 20)
  - "What Am I Reading" (Box 20)
  - "What are the Mass Media Doing to Our Culture?" (Box 20)
  - "What Baptists Believe" (Box 20)
  - "What Christ Proposes to Do" (Box 20)
  - "What Did You Do With 1951?" (Box 20)
  - "What Do Christians Owe to the Jews?" (Box 20)
  - "What Do We Mean By Temperance?" (Box 20)
  - "What Does It Add Up To?" (Box 20)
  - "What Doth Hinder?" (Box 20)
  - "What Doth Hinder Thee?" (Box 20)
  - "What God Hath Prepared" (Box 20)
  - "What Happens At Communion?" (Box 20)
  - "What Has Happened in Turkey?" (Box 20)
  - "What Hope For a United World?" (Box 20)
  - "What Is Salvation?" (Box 20)
  - "What Is Sin?" (Box 20)
  - "What Is Spirituality?" (Box 20)
  - "What Is the Soul?" (Box 20)
  - "What Men Miss" (Box 20)
  - "What Next For the Jews?" (Box 20)
  - "What Next in Prohibition?" (Box 20)
  - "What Price Christianity?" (Box 20)
  - "What Shall I Give?" (Box 20)
  - "What Shall We Do With 7,000 Consciences?" (Box 20)
  - "What Syllable?" (Box 20)
  - "What To Do With Criticism" (Box 20)
  - "What We Know About Death" (Box 20)
  - "What We Know About God" (Box 20)
  - "What We Know About Prayer" (Box 20)
  - "What We Know About Sin" (Box 20)
  - "What We Owe To Our Children" (Box 20)
  - "What Will the Churches Be Doing At Amsterdam?" (Box 20)
  - "What Would Jesus Do?" (Box 20)
  - "What's Happened in Mexico?" (Box 20)
  - "What's New in the World Council of Churches" (Box 20)
  - "What's Wrong With Our Evangelism?" (Box 20)
  - "When Christ Came From Nazareth" (Box 20)
  - "When Christ Invaded the Temple" (Box 20)
  - "When Churches Grow Younger" (Box 20)
  - "When God Blocks Our Way" (Box 20)
  - "When God Saves a Fool" (Box 20)
  - "When God's Glory Passes By" (Box 20)
  - "When Jesus Hungered" (Box 20)
  - "When Kings Go Out to Battle" (Box 20)
  - "When Kings Invade the Church" (Box 20)
  - "When Life Gets Too Big" (Box 20)
  - "When Majorities Are Wrong" (Box 20)
  - "When My Mother and Father Forsake Me!" (Box 20)
  - "When Paul Joined the Church" (Box 20)
  - "When the Tide Comes In" (Box 20)
  - "When They Had Sung a Hymn" (Box 20)
  - "When We Pray" (Box 21)
  - "When Youth Was Wrong" (Box 21)
  - "Where Does the Sky Begin" (Box 21)
  - "Where Faith Meets the Stars" (Box 21)
  - "Where Is Heaven?" (Box 21)
  - "Where Judgment Begins" (Box 21)
  - "Where Rivers Begin" (Box 21)
  - "Where the Saints Have Trod"" (Box 21)
  - "Where Two Seas Meet" (Box 21)
  - "Which Way America?" (Box 21)
  - "Which Way Is Forward?" (Box 21)
  - "While We Were Yet Sinners" (Box 21)
  - "Whispers in the Dark" (Box 21)
  - "White Houses in Black" (Box 21)
  - "White Indians" (Box 21)
  - "The White Man's Dungeon" (Box 21)
  - "Whither Bound?" (Box 21)
  - "The Witness and the Light" (Box 21)
  - "The Witness of the Five Wounds" (Box 21)
  - "Who Hath Sorrow?" (Box 21)
  - "Who Is Our Peace?" (Box 21)
  - "Who Is the New Minister?" (Box 21)
  - "Who Seeth In Secret?" (Box 21)
  - "Who Serves You?" (Box 21)
  - "Who's Afraid?" (Box 21)
  - "The Whole Armor of God" (Box 21)
  - "Why Christ Prayed" (Box 21)
  - "Why Do We Suffer?" (Box 21)
  - "Why Do You Baptize Your Baby?" (Box 21)
  - "Why Hitler?" (Box 21)
  - "Why I Am a Protestant" (Box 21)
  - "Why I Believe in the Church" (Box 21)
  - "Why I Chose the Ministry" (Box 21)
  - "Why I Put on the Sandals" (Box 21)
  - "Why Men Suffer" (Box 21)
  - "Why Spared?" (Box 21)
  - "Why Teach About Economic Aid?" (Box 21)
  - "Why the Bible Helps Me" (Box 21)
  - "Why the Church Press?" (Box 21)
  - "Why We Are Here" (Box 21)
  - "The Widow and the Unrighteous Judge" (Box 21)
  - "The Wine of God" (Box 21)
  - "Wings of the Morning" (Box 21)
  - "Winter in Solomon's Porch" (Box 21)
  - "Wiping the Blood Out of Our Eyes" (Box 21)
  - "The Witch of Endor" (Box 21)
  - "The Witness of the Five Wounds" (Box 21)
  - "The Word Became Flesh" (Box 21)
  - "The Word We Preach" (Box 21)
  - "The Working Character of Immortality" (Box 21)
  - "A Working Communion" (Box 21)
  - "The Working Equipment of the Bible School" (Box 21)
  - "The Works of Christ" (Box 21)
  - "World Conditions and the Church" (Box 21)
  - "The World and Its Wisdom" (Box 21)
  - "The World Mission" (Box 21)
  - "World Peace and the Atlantic Pact" (Box 21)
  - "The World's Fear of Righteous Men" (Box 21)
  - "The World's Rebuke" (Box 21)
  - "The World's Return to the Church" (Box 21)
  - "The World's Series" (Box 21)
  - "A Worthy Communion" (Box 21)
  - "Worshipping With Our Children" (Box 21)
  - "Wrestling With the Sunrise" (Box 21)
  - "1940-Year of Destiny" (Box 22)
  - "The Year of the Earthquake" (Box 22)
  - "The Year that King Uzziah Died" (Box 22)
  - "The Yearning of the Soul" (Box 22)
  - "Yesterday, Today, and Forever" (Box 22)
  - "Yesterday When It Is Past" (Box 22)
  - "You May Lose" (Box 22)
  - "Your Best" (Box 22)
  - "Young People-Young Churches-Young National" (Box 22)
  - "Youth At the Door" (Box 22)
  - "Youth For Christ-Old Age For Christ" (Box 22)
  - "Youth: Is It Entitled to Freedom?" (Box 22)
  - "Youth on the Ledges of Eternity" (Box 22)
  - "Youth Rebuilds Christian Brotherhood" (Box 22)
  - "The Zealot" (Box 22)
  - "The Zero Hour" (Box 22)
  - "Zion's Glad Morning" (Box 22)